Curriculum Vita

Niharika Ram

Cell: (+91) 7008354662)

Mail To: niharikaram10@gmail.com



Career Objective

Establish Self As a Value Based, Dedicated and Hardworking Developed Professional and used my skill and knowledge Capacity Building, Skill Development, Vocational Training for women Empowerments, Hospitality, family counseling, field monitoring, field mobilized, work Evaluation, Programme management, quality data management, quality data check and different work plane etc.

About Me

Myself Niharika Ram, working as a research assistant under a project Domestic Hygiene and Menstrual Hygiene under the supervision of the School of Public Health, KIIT University. I have seven (7) years of experience in the health department in many places in Odisha and West Bengal like Sambalpur, Bhubaneswar, Malkangiri, Korapt, Puri, Ganjam and Kolkata. I have completed my Master in Social Sciences. (MSW) Being a social science, I am very interested in working in the health sector and also deferent sector being a social science we can work as a medical social worker in any government hospital and private hospital. I am confident of fully handling administration, sales marketing sector successfully. If you allow me to do my work in this field, as a result, I can effectively increase my knowledge in this area

Professional Experience

- > Year of 2020 I was working on (Research Assistant) project of household sanitation and women's experience of menstrual hygiene under Swachha Bharat Mission (Clean India Mission) from the Kiit University, Kiit School Of Public Health (KSPH/KIMS) at Bhubaneswar.
- Year of 2019 (Psychology Counselor) Of State Govt. Of Odisha Under The Awareness Camp Of Person With Disabilities, Student, Citizens, Transgender & Drug Addicts For All District Of Odisha At Bhubaneswar.

- Year of 2019 I Was Worked On (Field Investigator) Of Research Study of Water and Sanitation and West Water Management from CYSD Organization at Bhubaneswar.
- > Year Of 2019 I Was Worked On (QC) Quality Check Officer, Field Monitoring And Office Documentation Work) Project Of AYUSHMAN BHARAT (NHRR) NATIONAL HEALTH RESEARCH REPOSITORY Govt. Of Odisha Bhubaneswar.
- Year Of 2018 To 2019 Lead To (Project Coordinator) Of Odisha Livelihood Mission Undertaking Process Monitoring Of SHG Livelihood, SHG Financial Literacy, SHG Capacity Building Training, SHG Vocational Training, And Marketing Management at Society Valued Services (SVS) Org. Bhubaneswar
- > Year Of 2017 To 2018 (Lead To Livelihood Coordinator Resource Person) Of For Paradeep Phosphates Limited CSR Project on the Domains of Health, Wash, Community Mobilization and Livelihoods and Skill Development Training Programme.
- Year of 2017 April (Lead To Field Investigator) Of KIIT TBI Research Associate Social Audit And Social Impact Assessment For Essel Mining, Aditya Birla Limited at Keonjhar.
- Year of 2016 June to December (Documentation and District Coordinator) Of Govt.
 Of India, UNDP Implementing The Electronic Vaccine Intelligence Network
 (EVIN), Assessment For 30 Districts Of Odisha.
- Year Of 2015 To 2016 I Was Worked On (Project Coordinator) Project Of Western Orissa Child Marriage Prevention And Sexual Reproductive Health Rights (SRHR) at Organization Of (SIDI) Sambalpur Integrated Development Institute Of Odisha.
- Year Of 2014 (HIV/AIDS COUNSELOR) Project Of (FSW TI) Female Sex Worker Target Intervention at West Bengal Kolkata Musidabad and the River of Farrka West Bengal.
- > Year Of 2007 To 2010 I Was Worked On (Teacher ship And Social Activity) Of CSR Aiditya Birla Jan Seva Trust.

EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATION

✓ M.S.W (Master Of Social Work) from OASIS : 2010-2012
 College, Balasore Utkal University of (Culture) Odisha .

√ +3 Bachelor of Arts. (H-Political Sciences) from

Padampur. : 2007-2010

College, Kendhujhar North University, Baripada Odisha.

√ +2 Higher Secondary Education in Science Stream

From Govt. Junior College Koira, Sundergarh, Odisha : 2005-2007

 \checkmark 10th Secondary Education from Gopobandhu

Govt. High School Sundergarh, Odisha : 2004-2005

In Study Exposure:

Training & Workshop Attended:

• Awareness Programmed On T.B (Tuber Colossuses) and Leprosy Form Balasore.

Practical Study tour:

- Rural Camp at Patsani Pur Village of Udula Gp of Baripada Block of Mayurbhanj District for 7 Days.
- Study Tour at Khadia & Mankidia Village of Mayurbhanj District for a Day.

Research Work (Aditya Birla Iron Mines in Sundergarh, Odisha)

• Impact of Mines on the Economic Development of Tribal People Related to Livelihood, Health and Education.

Skills

- Computer Skill.
- Documentation.
- Programme Management.
- Strong Decision Making Capability.
- Leadership Work
- Field monitoring
- Strong counseling for any propose

Software Skills

- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Word
- Microsoft Power Point
- Different Networking work
- Data Entry work for any different software

My Strengths

- Ability to Motivate And Gain Support In Teamwork.
- Ability to Work under Stress and Hard Working.
- Sound Motivating and Development Skills.
- Ability to Leadership work for different field place.
- Ability to coordinate for any Networking work
- Ability to management for Different Project/official work.
- Ability to HR Management.

Hobbies & Interest

- Interested In any Social Activities.
- Listening Music & Making New Friends.
- Help for any need person.
- Counseling for any problematic person

Extra Curricular Activities

- Participating In Different Social & Cultural Programs.
- Skills it demonstrates: confidence, self-presentation, collaboration, attention to detail, creativity.
- Volunteering work for social work related.

Academic Background

- MSW (Master in Social Work) "A" Grade.
- BA (Bachelor in Arts) With Political science Hones. "B" Grade.
- +2 (Inter) "B" Grade.
- 10th (Metric) "B" Grade.

Languages Known

Oriya, Hindi, and English

Personal Details:-

Father's Name : Sri. Ganesh Prasad Ram

Mother's Name : Smt. Rekha Ram

Sex : Female

Category : General

Religion : Hindu

Marital Status : Unmarried

Blood Group : O+

Nationality : Indian

Present Address

Bhubaneswar

Dist - Khurdha (Odisha)

Niharika Ram.